Finding Aid for the The Donald Grady Davidson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Appendix C-Fugitives and Agrarians-List of Newspaper Clippings, 1924 -1936
  - Observer (Charlotte, N. C.): The Literary Lantern, duplicate of Nov. 29., Nov. 30, 1930
  - New York Herald Tribune: "What is the Southland?" review of I'll Take My Stand by Virginia Moore., Nov. 30, 1930
  - Nashville Tennessean, "Book Review," of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 6, 1930
  - Herald (Columbia, Tn.): review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 6, 1930
  - Gazette (Emporia, Kansas): "The Real South," review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 6, 1930
  - New York Sun: "South, Old and New," review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 6, 1930
  - Times Dispatch (Richmond, Va.): "Four Southern Champions," by Allen Cleaton., Dec. 7, 1930
  - Journal (Knoxville, Tn.): "Book Review" of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 8, 1930
  - Tribune (New Orleans, La.): "Southerners Make Plea for Agrarianism/ 12 Born in Rural south, Urge Stand Against Industrialism/ Tulane Professor Includes His Views/ Philosophy of Group Set Forth in I'll Take My Stand.", Dec. 8, 1930
  - Nashville Banner: "Knickerbocker to Debate Ransom.", Dec. 10, 1930
  - News (Buffalo, N. Y.): review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 13, 1930
  - News (Chattanooga, Tn.): review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 13, 1930
  - Enquirer (Cincinnati, Ohio): review of I'll Take My Stand, Dec. 13, 1930
  - News Sentinel (Knoxville, Tn.): "Can South Go Back To Agrarian Culture?", Dec. 14, 1930
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, Tn): Cossitt Book Notes-"Southern Agrarian Tradition.", Dec. 14, 1930
  - Constitution (Atlanta, Ga.): citation of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 14, 1930
  - Star Telegram (Fort Worth, Tx.): " 12 Valiants Take Stand for Old Life/ Symposium of Southerners on Necessity for Agrarian Revival," review of I'll Take My Stand by Alex Stedman., Dec. 14, 1930
  - News (Dallas, Texas): "Machine Age Problems Up Before Forum/ Half Way Point Betwween Industrial South and Agricultural Sought/Writer Lectures/ Howard M. Jones Formerly University of Texas Teacher., Dec. 15, 1930
  - The Outlook, advertisement for I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 17, 1930
  - Baltimore Evening Sun: " Crusade in Dixie," comment on I'll Take My Stand and agrarianism by Virginius Dabney., Dec. 18, 1930
  - Commerce and Finance: "Tradition and the South," review of I'll Take My Stand by L.B.J., Dec. 18, 1930
  - N. Y. Telegram: " South's Stories and Problems in Two Volumes/ I'll Take My Stand, Dozen Essays by Southerners with Eyes on Post," review of I'll Take My Stand, and Golden Tales of the Old South, by Oakley Johnson., Dec. 19, 1930
  - Folder
  - Saturday Review of Literature: "Back to the Hand," review of I'll Take My Stand, by William S. Knickerbocker., Dec. 20, 1930
  - Leaf Chronicle (Clarksville, Tn.): "Library Notes.", Dec. 20, 1930
  - Dispatch (Columbus, Ohio): "Protest From the South Against Industrialism Twelve Pleas for Restoration of Agrarian Life of Cultured Leisure There and Elsewhere in the Country," review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 21, 1930
  - News (Dallas, Tx.): "Symposium Presents Twelve Southerners/These Men Emphasize Menace of Machine Age and Urge Return to Farm Life.", Dec. 21, 1930
  - Journal Courier (New Haven, Ct.): review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 24, 1930
  - Times (Chattanooga, Tn.): "Ransom-Barr Debate Scheduled for Jan. 9.", Dec. 26, 1930
  - Post (Chicago, Ill.): "Public Affairs," review of I'll Take My Stand by Hilda Joseph., Dec. 26, 1930
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, Tn.): "University Women To Hear Talk On Southern Writers.", Dec. 27, 1930
  - News (Charlotte, N. C.): "Southern Ideal Called Oways (sic) Out of Black Industrial Fog/ Leaders Declare Pulmotor Methods of Stimulating Business And Cultural Insensibility False," review of I'll Take My Stand., Dec. 28, 1930
  - N. Y. Morning World: The Firsts Reader, "A New Shepard." Citation of I'll Take My Stand by Harry Hansen., Dec. 30, 1930
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, Tn.): "Young Writers Is Topic/Penn Warren To Address University Women This Afternoon.", Jan. 2, 1931
  - News (Birmingham, Ala.): "Back to the Land Urged To Save South's Soul.", Jan. 4, 1931
  - The New York Times Book Review: "Industrialism and the Agrarian Tradition In the South/Two Forces Are at War for Control of the Future Below the Mason And Dixon Line.", Jan. 4, 1931
  - World Herald (Omaha, Nebraska): "Saving the South," review of I'll Take My Stand., Jan. 4, 1931
  - News Sentinel (Knoxville, Tn.): "Takes His Stand.", Jan. 4, 1931
  - Times-Picayune (New Orleans, La.): comment on I'llTake My Stand by John McClure., Jan. 4, 1931
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, Tn.): "I'll Take My Stand- a Review," by Virginia Frazier Boyle., Jan. 5, 1931
  - Nashville Tennessean: "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Jan. 7, 1931
  - Advocate (Baton Rouge, La.): "Book Is Dedicated to W. L. Fleming By 12 Authors/Former L. S. U. History Professor Is Honored With Dedication of I'll Take My Stand., Jan. 9, 1931
  - Journal (Knoxville, Tn.): "Last Call to U.T. Playwrights.", Jan. 9, 1931
  - Star News (Pasadena, Cal.): "I'll Take My Stand.", Jan. 10, 1931
  - Journal (Knoxville, Tn.): "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Jan. 10, 1931
  - Press (Savannah, Ga.): "The Literary Lantern," by Paul Green., Jan. 10, 1931
  - News (Chattanooga, Tn.): no title, letter to the Editor re: the Young Confederates by Alfred Mynders., Jan. 10, 1931
  - Courier Journal (Louisville, Ky.): "To Warn the Wavering South," Review of I'llTake My Stand., Jan. 11, 1931
  - Nation: " So did King Canute," review of I'll Take My Stand, by Henry Hazlitt., Jan. 14, 1931
  - Journal (Knoxville, Tn.): "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Jan. 15, 1931
  - News Observer (Raleigh, N. C.): "Alumni Book Club Lists Four Books/ Unique Loan Literary Plan Creating Interest.", Jan. 18, 1931
  - Twin City Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N. C.): "Industrial Move Regarded Askance/What Can Be Saved of the Old South is Symposium Topic.", Jan. 18, 1931
  - Courant (Hartford, Ct.): "Twelve Southerners Take Their Stand.", Jan. 18, 1931
  - Times Union (Jacksonville, Fla.): no title, citation of Ransom-Barr Debate., Jan. 18, 1931
  - Dispatch (Columbus, Ohio): "Modern Mass Production-Is It a Boon or A Menace"-mention of I'll Take My Stand as a notable book., Jan. 18, 1931
  - Nashville Tennessean: "Carnegie Library.", Jan. 19, 1931
  - Gazette (Gastonia, N. C.): "Twelve ‘Young Rebels' Speak Out For The Agrarian South/ Southern Writers Deplore Coming of Industrialism in I'll Take My Stand.", Jan. 21,1931
  - Saturday Review of Literature: "I'll Take My Stand"; letter to the editor By Helen Hill., Jan. 24, 1931
  - News (Hollywood, Ca.): no title, citation of Ransom-Barr Debate., Jan. 24, 1931
  - Star News (Wilmington, N. C.): "Alumni Book Club Lists for January.", Jan. 25, 1931
  - Twin City Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N. C.): "Four Books Are Listed by Alumni Book Club.", Jan. 25, 1931
  - Free Press (Detroit, Michigan): "I'll Take My Stand," comment on., Jan. 25, 1931
  - Nashville Tennessean: "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Jan. 30, 1931
  - News (Birmingham, Ala.): "Joint Authority.", Feb. 1, 1931
  - News (Savannah, Ga.); "Twelve Southerners Consider South's Ideals," I'll Take My Stand reviewed by Adah Young., Feb. 1, 1931
  - New York Times: "Texas Is Feeling Its Cultural Oats"-mention of I'll Take My Stand., Feb. 1, 1931
  - Folder
  - Commercial Appeal (Memphis, Tn.): "I Reckon So," by T. H. Alexander., Feb. 2, 1931
  - Transcript (Boston, Mass.): "The South and Industrialism.", Feb. 4, 1931
  - _________ "Leaders Declare Pulmotor Methods of Stimulating Business and Cultural Insensibility False." Review of I'll Take My Stand by C. K. Brown of Davidson College.
  - Chattanooga News (Chattanooga, Tn.): "G.K. Chesterton, English Notable ‘Stranded' in Chattanooga, Agrees with Ideals of Young Confederates.'", Feb. 4, 1931
  - Tribune (Salt Lake City, Utah): "New Rebellion in South," editorial., Feb. 8, 1931
  - News (Dallas, Tx.): "Southwest Review Offers Material for Discussion.", Feb. 8, 1931
  - American (Atlanta, Ga.): "12 Southerners Collaborate on Book., Feb. 8, 1931
  - Record (Columbia, S. C.) no title, citation of I'll Take My Stand., Feb. 8, 1931
  - Journal (Atlanta, Ga.): "Emory's Notable Institute.", Feb. 9, 1931
  - Christian Science Monitor (Boston, Mass.): "Rise of Industry in South Draws Diverse Views/ Condemned as Menace to Culture and Defended in Debate at Atlanta.", Feb. 14, 1931
  - New York Times: "Regional Culture," editorial., Feb. 15, 1931
  - State (Columbia, S. C.): "The Literary Highway.", Feb. 15, 1931
  - Times Union (Jacksonville, Florida): "Twelve Southerners With a Mirror," By Edgar Legare Pennington., Feb. 15, 1931
  - Tribune (New Orleans, La.): "The South.", Feb. 22, 1931
  - Times (Seattle, Washington): "World Calls in List of New Books/Rear Admiral R. E. Coontz's Autobiography Among New Volumes at Public Library.", March 1, 1931
  - Daily Herald (Columbia, Tn.): "Agrarian Issue Will Be Debated in City Tonight/Joint Discussion Between Knickerbocker and Davidson Will Begin At 8 O'Clock/Judge Whitthorne Will Act as Moderator for Debate/ Speakers Will Be Presented to the Audience by the Sponsorers of Notable Intellectual Event Here.", May 21, 1931
  - Yale News Literary Supplement: "The New South," review of I'll Take My Stand by G. W. Glenn., May 27, 1931
  - New York Herald Tribune Books: "A Weekend at Mr. Jefferson's University," by Emily Clark., Nov. 8, 1931
  - Folder
  - Newspaper Clippings and Reviews about Who Owns America? (April 29, 1936-May 19, 1936)
  - News (Chicago, Ill.): "The Book of the Week (Number 18)" review of Who Owns America? By Sterling North., April 29, 1936
  - Star (Wilmington, Delaware): citation of Who Owns America?, May 3, 1936
  - Courier Journal (Louisville, Ky.): citation of Who Owns America?, May 3, 1936
  - News (Detroit, Michigan): "Arguments On the Necessity of Small-Scale Industry and the Return to a ‘Property State.'" By Clyde Beck., May 3, 1936
  - News (Dallas, Tx.): "Symposium Is Revision of Agrarian Philosophy/New Manifesto Is Unlike Earlier Book.", May 3, 1936
  - Washington Post: "No End of Books" citation of Who Owns America?, May 3, 1936
  - News (Buffalo, N. Y.): "Who Owns America? Is Symposium Theme" review By Charles Hanson Towne., May 5, 1936
  - American (N.Y. N. Y.): review of Who Owns America? By Charles Hanson Towne., May 5, 1936
  - Herald Examiner (Chicago, Ill.): review of Who Owns America?, May 5, 1936
  - Post (Cincinnati, Ohio): "Land of the Free Insurgent America" review Of Who Owns America? b y James D. Earley., May 6, 1936
  - Post (Worcester, Mass.): "Effectively Answered.", May 9, 1936
  - Beacon - Journal (Akron, Ohio): review of Who Owns America?, May 9, 1936
  - Herald-Tribune (N.Y., N.Y.): "Who Owns This Country in Which We Live/Big Business, Say These Anti-Socialist Authors; They Want Ownership Distributed," review of Who Owns America? By Stringfellow Barr., May 10, 1936
  - New York Times, " A Share for All in America/ Mr. Agar and Mr. Tate Sponsor ‘A New Declaration of Independence,'" review of Who Owns America? By John Corbin., May 10, 1936
  - Times (Buffalo, N. Y.): "Volume Is Sure To Prove Provocative.", May 11, 1936
  - Journal of Commerce (Chicago, Ill.): " Something for Everybody In United States," review of Who Owns America?, May 16, 1936
  - Mid-Week Pictorial (N.Y, N. Y.): "A Call for Another Deal.", May 16, 1936
  - Star (Kansas City, Mo.): "American Problems.", May 16, 1936
  - Tribune (Minneapolis, Minn.): "Decentralization," review of Who Owns America?, May 17, 1936
  - Courier Journal (Louisville, Ky.): "Program for Patriots," a review of Who Owns America? by Russell Briney., May 17, 1936
  - Daily Worker (N. Y., N. Y.): "Books in Review," by John Stanley, notice Of Who Owns America?, May 19, 1936
  - New Era (Lancaster, Pa.): "The Literary Guidepost," by John Selby review of Who Owns America?, May 19, 1936
  - Twin City Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N.C.): "The Agrians State Their Case," Extracts from Who Owns America?, May 19, 1936
  - Post Star (Glens Falls, N.Y.): "About Books," by John Selby review of Who Owns America?, May 19, 1936
  - Press (Escanaba, Michigan): "The Literary Guidepost," by John Selby Review of Who Owns America?, May 21, 1936
  - Twin City Sentinel (Winston-Salem, N. C.): citation of Who Owns America?, May 21, 1936
  - Tribune (Holdenville, Okla.): "The Literary Guidepost," by John Selby Review of Who Owns America?, May 22, 1936
  - News Tribune (Waco, Texas): "Books," by John Selby, review of Who Owns America?, May 22, 1936
  - Gazette (Charleston, W. Va.): review of Who Owns America?, May 24, 1936
  - St. Louis Post-Dispatch: "Based on American Ideals," review of, May 24, 1936
- Who Owns America?
- DONALD DAVIDSON PAPERS
- APPENDIX D-SUBJECT FILES
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Major Peregrine Acland
  - Michael Arlen
  - Gertrude Atherton (2)
  - Mary Austin
  - Irving Babbitt
  - Margaret Culkin Banning
  - Sir James M. Barrie
  - Clive Bell
  - Silas Bent
  - Albert Beveridge
  - Princess Marthe Bibesco
  - Henri Biraud
  - Maxwell Bodenheim (2)
  - Louise Bogan
  - Johan Bojer (2)
  - James Boyd
  - Thomas Boyd
  - Rear Admiral W. E. D. Boyle
  - Ernest Brace
  - Breadloaf Inn, Vermont
  - James Henry Breasted
  - Heyward Broun
  - Katharine Brush
  - Konrad Bucovici
  - Thomas Burke
  - Com. Richard E. Byrd, U.S.N.
  - Henry Seidel Canby
  - Ada Jack Carver
  - Carl Carver
  - Catherine the Great
  - Robert W. Chambers
  - Stuart Chase
  - Dr. Joseph Collins
  - Grace Hazard Conkling
  - Hughes Cornell
  - e.e.cummings
  - Richard Curle
  - Miss Clemence Dane
  - E. M. Delafield
  - John Dewey (2)
  - Ward Donnance
  - Manhattan Transfer-John Dos Passos
  - Theodore Dreiser (2)
  - Isadore Duncan (2)
  - T. S. Eliot
  - Ralph Waldo Emerson
  - John Erskine
  - Susan Ertz
  - Jake Falstaff (pseudonym)
  - Charles Ferguson
  - H.M. King Feisal of Irak
  - Henry Ford
  - H.W. Freeman
  - V. H. M. Friedlaender
  - John Galsworthy
  - William Gerhardi
  - Herbert Adams Gibbons
  - Julian Green
  - Paul Green
  - Mrs. J. Borden Harriman
  - Lee Foster Hartman
  - Ernest Hemingway (3)
  - A. P. Herbert
  - Dorothy Heyward
  - Dubose Heyward (2)
  - Rupert Hughes
  - Fannie Hurst
  - Aldous Huxley
  - Andrew Jackson
  - Marquis James
  - Robinson Jeffers (2)
  - Generals Joffre, Haig and Foch
  - Matthew Josephson (3)
  - Keat's "Endymion"
  - Helen Keller
  - Count Hermann Keyserling
  - Manuel Komfoft
  - Paul de Kruif
  - Peter Kyne
  - Ring Lardner
  - T. E. Lawrence from a portrait by Augustus John
  - Margaret Leech
  - B. H. Lehman
  - Sinclair Lewis
  - Herbert Lootner (sp?)
  - William McFee
  - Kenneth Macgowan
  - Heinrich Mann
  - Frances Marion
  - Frank Jewett Mather
  - Norman Matson
  - Somerset Maugham
  - - -Andre Maurois
  - Adah Isaacs Menken
  - Robert A. Millikan
  - Sarah Gertrude Millin
  - C. E. Montagne
  - Paul Elmer More
  - Gorham B. Munson
  - Benito Mussolini
  - Gustavus Myers
  - Beverly Nichols
  - Jessica Nelson North
  - Albert Bigelow Paine
  - Dorothy Parker
  - Anne Parrish
  - Vernon Lewis Pennington
  - William Lyon Phelps
  - Alexander Pope
  - Llewlyn Powys
  - Cale Young Rice
  - Lola Ridge
  - Carroll E. Robb
  - Elizabeth Madox Roberts
  - Edwin Arlington Robinson
  - James Harvey Robinson
  - O. E. Rolvaag (2)
  - Naomi G. Royde-Smith
  - Bertrand Russell
  - Michael Sadleir
  - Herbert Ravenel Sass (2)
  - Lyle Saxon (2)
  - Isador Schneider
  - Evelyn Scott
  - Grace Thompson Seton
  - Professor Robert Shafer
  - Dallas Lore Sharp
  - Upton Sinclair
  - Sir Ronald Storrs
  - T. S. Stribling
  - Frank Swinnerton (?)
  - Booth Tarkington (3)
  - Albert Payson Terhune
  - Louis Untermeyer (4)
  - S.S. Van Dine (3)
  - Dorothy Van Doren
  - Mark Van Doren
  - C. Van Doren
  - Henry Van Dyke
  - Hendrik Willem Van Loon
  - Carl Van Vechten
  - Mary Heaton Vorse
  - Hugh Walpole
  - Jacob Wasserman
  - H. G. Wells
  - Rebecca West
  - Stewart Edward White
  - Walter White
  - Thornton Wilder
  - Jesse Lynch Williams
  - Woodrow Wilson (2)
  - John K. Winkler
  - P. G. Wodehouse
  - Thomas Wolfe
  - W. E. Woodward (2)
  - Virginia Woolf
  - Elinor Wylie
  - Alvin York
  - Francis Brett Young
  - Stark Young